- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- * Ohh... *
-*哦...*
* Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? *
*谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ *
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he *
- * 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * If nautical nonsense
be something you wish *
- *如果航海废话
成为你所希望的*
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- * Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish *
- * 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通 *
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
*
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[lively tropical music]
[活泼的热带音乐]
*
- Wow, another Mermaid Man
reboot.
- 哇，又一个美人鱼男人
重新启动。
It's how I always reimagined
the reboot would be remade.
这就是我总是重新想象的方式
重新启动将被重新启动。
Ooh, cold knees.
哦，膝盖冰凉。
- Oh, you say
you got cold knees?
- 哦，你说
你膝盖冰凉吗？
Icy joints,
Siberian patellas?
关节冰冷，
西伯利亚髌骨？
What you need is
a pair of long pants.
你需要的是
一条长裤。
- Long pants?
- 长裤？
Well, I don't think
I'm ready for long pants.
嗯，我不认为
我已经准备好穿长裤了
- Nonsense.
- 废话。
No fella should walk around
with shiver shins.
任何人都不应该四处走动
小腿颤抖。
Give yourself a leg up.
给自己一个支持。
Join the trouser troops.
加入裤子大军吧。
all chanting:
Hup, hup, hup!
所有人都在喊口号：
呵呵，呵呵，呵呵！
- Don't be a slacker.
Wear slacks.
- 别做一个懒鬼。
穿休闲裤。
- Uh, well,
I don't--uh...
- 呃，好吧，
我不——呃...
Okay!
好的！
How do I look?
我看起来怎么样？
- Excuse me, sir,
- 对不起，先生，
I was just talking
to a little, baby,
我只是在说话
一点点，宝贝，
schoolboy a second ago.
前一秒还是个小学生。
About yea high.
大约是高。
Wh--wh--what?
It's you!
什——什——什么？
是你！
I didn't recognize you
with your mature,
我没认出你
带着成熟的你，
grown-up, long pants.
长大了，长裤了。
- You're pulling my leg, Mister.
- 你在开我的玩笑，先生。
I don't look like a man.
我看起来不像个男人。
Do I?
我是吗？
- Hey, man.
- 嘿，伙计。
- He called me a man!
- 他称我为男人！
And my knees are a perfect
72 degrees.
我的膝盖非常完美
72度。
- [clicks tongue]
- [咔嚓舌头]
[all gasping, exclaiming]
[全都喘着粗气，惊呼]
[jazzy music]
[爵士乐]
*
[all exclaiming]
[所有人惊呼]
- You can see who wears
the pants in here!
- 你可以看到谁穿着
裤子在这里！
- Is that my daddy?
- 那是我爸爸吗？
- I wish.
- 我希望。
- Uh, excuse me, sir.
- 呃，对不起，先生。
That door is
for employees only.
那扇门是
仅供员工使用。
Oh, SpongeBob.
哦，海绵宝宝。
Hmm.
[sniffing]
唔。
[嗅嗅]
There is something
different about you today.
有东西
今天的你有所不同。
You seem more able-bodied.
你看起来更能干了。
- Well, must be the long pants.
- 嗯，一定是长裤。
- [squeals]
So they are!
- [尖叫声]
他们就是这样！
You run the register today.
你今天运行登记册。
In the galley with you,
Mr. Squidward.
和你一起在厨房里，
章鱼哥先生。
And start cooking.
并开始做饭。
- But Mr. Krabs, why?
- 但是蟹老板，为什么呢？
- Well, just look.
- 好吧，看看吧。
SpongeBob's got long pants on,
海绵宝宝穿上长裤了
and you've got...none.
而你却……没有。
all:
Oh!
全部：
哦！
- Aah!
[crashes]
- 啊啊！
[崩溃]
- Oh, I could get used to
this job.
-哦，我会习惯的
这份工作。
Hey, Squidward,
what's on sale this week?
嘿，章鱼哥，
本周有什么特价商品？
- Nothing.
There's never a sale.
- 没有什么。
从来没有销售。
- Squidward, how much
is the senior discount?
- 章鱼哥，多少钱
是高级折扣吗？
- There's no senior discount.
- 没有高级折扣。
[sizzling]
[嘶嘶声]
[grunting, groaning]
[咕哝，呻吟]
Aah! Ooh! Aah!
啊啊！哦！啊啊！
- Squidward?
- What?
- 章鱼哥？
- 什么？
- What do I do when the register
is $2,000 short?
- 注册后我该怎么办
还差2000美元吗？
- Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- 哇，哇，哇，
哇，哇，哇，哇。
All right, all right.
That's enough.
好吧，好吧。
这就够了。
I see it was a mistake
to put you behind the register.
我发现这是一个错误
把你放在收银台后面。
You're just looking too good
for such insipid, menial work.
你只是看起来太好了
从事如此乏味、卑微的工作。
- [grouchy blubbering]
- [不满地抽泣]
- You should be
the maitre d'.
- 你应该是
领班。
Greeting customers
when they come in.
问候顾客
当他们进来的时候。
Charming the pants off
of everyone
脱掉裤子的魅力
每个人的
with your long pants.
和你的长裤。
- [laughing]
Okay.
- [笑]
好的。
Hi.
How are you?
你好。
你好吗？
Looking good.
看起来不错。
Mustard with that?
All right.
芥末配那个？
好的。
How is that patty
treating you, sir?
那个馅饼怎么样
先生，在治疗您吗？
- Are you an angel?
- 你是天使吗？
- No, merely a man.
- 不，只是一个男人。
A man in long pants.
一个穿着长裤的男人。
- [loud gobbling]
- [大声狼吞虎咽]
[slurps, spits]
[吸吮，吐口水]
- Aah!
Aah!
- 啊啊！
啊啊！
Aah!
- [slobbering]
- [流口水]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[whines]
[哀鸣]
Aah!
啊啊！
Oh, my precious long pants!
哦，我珍贵的长裤！
- What's wrong, slick?
-怎么了，光滑的？
You're not having trouble
你没有遇到麻烦
with your pants, are you?
和你的裤子一起，是吗？
- Nothing like that, Mr. Krabs.
- 没有那样的事，蟹老板。
I just don't think
I'm maitre d' material.
我只是不认为
我是材料领班。
- Yeah, you're right.
- 是的，你说得对。
You're too good for this place.
你太适合这个地方了。
[customers belching]
[顾客打嗝]
- As much as I'd
hate to admit it,
- 尽我所能
不愿意承认，
I've outgrown the Krusty Krab.
我已经长大了，吃不了蟹堡王了。
Time for me to move on.
我该继续前进了。
[heroic music]
[英雄音乐]
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
*
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
*
- Where is he going?
- 他要去哪里？
- A place called manhood.
- 一个叫做男子气概的地方。
- Doris, I insist.
- 多丽丝，我坚持说。
- Don't be silly.
- 别傻了。
- Allow me, ladies.
- 请允许我，女士们。
I should pay.
我应该付钱。
After all, I am a man.
毕竟，我是一个男人。
And I'm wearing...
[whistles]
而我穿着...
[口哨声]
- What an inseam.
- 多么内缝啊。
- And those pleats were
pretty easy on the eyes.
- 那些褶皱是
对眼睛很容易。
[boat roaring]
[船的轰鸣声]
- Ah, shrimp!
- 啊，虾！
Oh, dry cleaning in one hour.
哦，一小时内干洗。
- Uh, ticket, please.
- 呃，请买票。
- Has it already
been an hour?
- 已经有了吗
一个小时了？
One more time!
[laughing]
再一次！
[笑]
[whistles]
Ah, yeah.
[口哨声]
啊，是的。
[brakes squealing]
[刹车尖叫声]
- Congratulations,
you passed your driver's test.
- 恭喜，
你通过了驾驶考试。
- Wahoo!
- 哇呼！
- You know, I never took
- 你知道，我从来没有拿过
the driver's test
with long pants.
驾驶员考试
搭配长裤。
I'll do it!
我会做的！
- There goes a real man.
- 一个真正的男人走了。
- Let's try parallel parking.
- 让我们尝试平行停车。
Now take it slow.
现在慢慢来。
A little faster.
快一点。
Oh! Oh!
Whoa! Ugh!
哦！哦！
哇！啊!
[metal crashing]
[金属碰撞]
- Hey, I think I'm getting
the hang of this.
- 嘿，我想我明白了
这就是诀窍。
- I was gonna fail you
and send you to jail,
- 我本来会让你失望的
并将你送进监狱，
but because of
those long pants,
但因为
那些长裤，
and all the blood rushing
to my head, you pass.
和所有的血液奔腾
在我看来，你过去了。
- I finally got
my driver's license.
-我终于得到了
我的驾驶执照。
- Oh, oh!
Lock your doors.
- 哦，哦！
锁好门。
Bar your windows.
It's the end of the world!
把窗户关上。
这是世界末日！
- Help wanted?
- 把招工广告？
Now this seems like
a long pants establishment.
现在这看起来像
长裤店
Today's special is a most
amusing Indian Ocean
今天的特别是最
有趣的印度洋
sea grass, handpicked
by indigenous prawns,
海草，手工采摘
由本土虾，
pre-chewed by local manatees
由当地海牛预先咀嚼
and then smothered
in a rich, red algae.
然后闷死
在丰富的红藻中。
[all muttering]
[大家嘀咕]
- Extraordinary.
- 非凡的。
And may I add,
those are very
我可以补充一下，
那些非常
impressive britches
you're wearing.
令人印象深刻的裤子
你穿着。
- Britches?
- 马裤？
Oh, these old things.
哦，这些老东西了。
- What is your name?
- 你叫什么名字？
- SpongeBob--
- [clears throat]
- 海绵宝宝 -
- [清喉咙]
- SpongeRobert.
- 海绵罗伯特.
- Well, SpongeRobert,
how would you like to join us?
- 嗯，海绵罗伯特，
您想加入我们吗？
We're going to a party.
我们要去参加一个聚会。
- Boy, would I?
I love parties!
- 男孩，我会吗？
我喜欢聚会！
[smug laughter]
[得意的笑声]
[elegant music playing]
【优雅的音乐演奏】
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
*
- What are you looking
for, SpongeRobert?
- 你在看什么
对于，海绵罗伯特？
- I'm looking for the party.
- 我正在寻找派对。
- This is the party.
- 这是聚会。
*
- Well, where's the party hats?
- 那么，派对帽子在哪里？
Where's the cake and the clown?
蛋糕和小丑在哪里？
You can't have a party
without a clown.
你不能举办派对
没有小丑。
- Oh, SpongeRobert.
- 哦，海绵罗伯特。
If it weren't for your pants,
如果不是你的裤子
I'd take you for the type
of immature ignoramus
我会选择你的类型
不成熟的无知者
that would frequent
the Krusty Krab.
会经常
蟹堡王。
- [chuckles nervously]
Yeah.
- [紧张地笑]
是的。
[dolphin chattering]
[海豚叽叽喳喳]
Hey, what's that?
嘿，那是什么？
The Mermaid Man
and Barnacle Boy movie
人鱼男
和藤壶男孩电影
is opening tonight!
今晚开业！
Wow!
I totally forgot.
哇！
我完全忘记了。
Hey, guys, I've got an idea.
嘿，伙计们，我有一个主意。
Let's all go to
the Mermaid Man movie.
我们都去
人鱼男电影。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
You're incorrigible, but
the cinema is a delightful idea.
你已经无可救药了，但是
电影院是一个令人愉快的主意。
There's a foreign film
at the art house
有一部外国电影
在艺术之家
I've been meaning to see.
我一直想去看看
It's called, "The Table."
它的名字叫“桌子”。
[high-pitched whistling]
[高亢的口哨声]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
[cat meowing]
[猫喵喵叫]
- I don't get it.
- 我不明白。
We've been staring at this table
for three hours.
我们一直盯着这张桌子
三个小时。
That table could use a cleaning.
那张桌子需要清洁一下。
- Shh!
- 嘘！
Some people are trying
to enjoy lé cinema.
有些人正在尝试
享受 lé 电影院。
- Oh, hey, Squidward.
- 哦，嘿，章鱼哥。
Hey, do you understand
what this movie's about?
嘿嘿，你明白吗
这部电影是关于什么的？
- Nobody does.
It's art.
- 没有人这样做。
这是艺术。
Now sit down!
现在坐下！
- Hey, Squidward?
- What?
- 嘿，章鱼哥？
- 什么？
- Are you remembering to
flip the patties clockwise?
- 你还记得吗
顺时针翻转馅饼？
It's very important
because the heat--
这非常重要
因为热量——
- Please, sit down!
- 请坐！
- I'm sorry, sir.
- 对不起，先生。
You're being too loud.
你太大声了。
I'm going to have to
ask you to leave.
我将不得不
请你离开。
- Uh, wait, Squidward!
- 呃，等等，章鱼哥！
I'll walk you out!
我送你出去！
- [grumbling]
- [抱怨]
- Squidward!
- 章鱼哥！
- Hey, SpongeBob!
- 嘿，海绵宝宝！
Y'all going to see
the Mermaid Man movie with us?
你们都会看到
和我们一起看美人鱼人电影吗？
- SpongeRobert, yoo-hoo.
- 海绵罗伯特，哟吼。
Are you coming?
你来吗？
We're going to drink
some more coffee
我们要去喝酒
再喝点咖啡
and watch the nightly news.
并观看晚间新闻。
- Wow, that sounds pretty
grown up, SpongeRobert.
- 哇，听起来不错
长大了，海绵罗伯特。
- My pants say
yes, yes, yes,
- 我的裤子说
是的，是的，是的，
but my heart says no.
但我的心说不。
I wanna see
the Mermaid Man movie.
我想看看
人鱼男电影。
- [laughs]
Now you really sound like
- [笑]
现在你听起来真的像
one of those nitwits that
frequents the Krusty Krab.
那些白痴之一
经常光顾蟹堡王。
- Not only am I
one of those nitwits,
- 不光是我
那些白痴之一，
I actually work there!
我实际上在那里工作！
[angelic chorus]
[天使合唱]
- Ugh!
A peasant in long pants.
- 呃！
一个穿长裤的农民。
- Social-climbing sponge.
- 社交攀登海绵。
- Poser!
- 装腔作势！
- Let's leave
this bottom-feeder.
- 我们离开吧
这个底部进料器。
- Attaboy!
- 阿塔博伊！
I got you a ticket
just in case.
我给你买了票
以防万一。
- [gasps]
Really?
- [喘气]
真的吗？
[exciting music]
[激动人心的音乐]
- I'm sorry,
you can't come in.
- 对不起，
你不能进来。
This movie is too silly
这电影太傻了
for a cultivated gentleman
of your pant length.
对于一位有教养的绅士
你的裤子长度。
House rules.
房子规则。
- What?
- 什么？
"Rated for those
in knee-highs only"?
“评价为那些
只穿及膝”？
Oh, I hate these pants!
哦，我讨厌这条裤子！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Get off!
下车！
[horn blaring, tires screeching]
[喇叭声、轮胎摩擦声]
Aah!
Oh!
啊啊！
哦！
[crashes]
[崩溃]
Ah, now I know I'm an adult,
啊，现在我知道我已经是个成年人了，
because I've been ripped off
by these defective pants.
因为我被骗了
就因为这些有缺陷的裤子。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- What's going on?
- 这是怎么回事？
How pathetic.
多么可悲啊。
A man in long pants crying.
一个穿着长裤的男人在哭泣。
- [sighing, sniffling]
- [叹气，吸鼻子]
Mr. Krabs, why aren't you
watching the movie?
蟹老板，你为什么不呢？
看电影？
- How can I watch the movie
- 我怎样才能看电影
with all this blubbering
going on out here?
伴随着所有这些哭泣
这里发生什么事了？
- Oh, Mr. Krabs,
I'm not ready for long pants.
-哦，蟹老板先生，
我还没准备好穿长裤。
I want my short pants back,
我想要回我的短裤
but I can't because
these are stuck on me.
但我不能因为
这些都粘在我身上。
- Oh, for Pete's sake.
- 哦，看在皮特的份上。
Sorry about the legs, boy.
对不起，孩子的腿。
- [laughs]
It's okay.
- [笑]
没关系。
I'm a sponge, remember?
我是一块海绵，记得吗？
- [laughs]
Well, good!
- [笑]
嗯，很好！
Then I want you back on
the grill tomorrow morning.
然后我要你回来
明天早上烧烤。
And if it makes you
feel any more manly,
如果它让你
感觉更有男人味了
you can do your grilling
outdoors.
你可以烧烤
户外。
- Sounds great!
- 听起来很棒！
And I'll be driving to work.
我会开车去上班。
- Wait a minute!
- 等一下！
Oh, no, you don't.
哦，不，你不知道。
Not with those short pants.
不适合那些短裤。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- I don't know what
that was all about,
- 我不知道什么
这就是全部，
but I'm glad it's over.
但我很高兴一切都结束了。